Omogbare Louis Ekpenga

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Email: ekpenga9000@gmail.com

Phone: 437-559-4221

LinkedIn:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/omogb

areekpenga/

Github: github.com/ekpenga9000 Location: Lethbridge, Alberta.

PROFILE

Passionate front-end developer with over 5 years of experience successfully delivering elegant and performant web solutions.
Completed and maintained 15+ projects utilizing HTML, CSS/SASS, Tailwind CSS, JavaScript and TypeScript, with expertise in React.js, React Query, Node.js and Next.js.

SKILLS

HTML, SASS, JavaScript, TypeScript, React.js, Next.js, Redux ToolKit, MySQL, Node.js, Docker, Kubernetes, Ingress-nginx, REST APIs, Microservices, Git, GitHub, Figma, wireframing, Jest, Agile Methodologies, Communication, Requirements gathering.

REFERENCES

Name: Clement Esene Organisation: BIPOC foundation Email: clement@bipocfoundation.org Relationship: Supervisor (Manager) at BIPOC Foundation Lethbridge.

Name: Daniil Molodkov Organisation: BrainStation

Email: <u>dmolodkov@brainstation.io</u> Relationship: Lead Educator and Team

Lead, Software Engineering.

PROJECTS

Lead Developer | Kubi

NOV 2023, A Collaborative project management application.

• A full-stack application built using JavaScript, Redux toolkit, React.js, JWT, Node.js, and MySQL.

Lead Developer | Olique Olick

AUG 2023, A social media application

 A full-stack application built using JavaScript, Redux toolkit, React.js, Node.js, OAuth, JWT, and MySQL.

EDUCATION

BrainStation | Diploma, Software Engineering

Jun 2023 - Aug 2023, Toronto, ON

Moat Academy | Diploma, Full-Stack Web Development

Apr 2022 - Jul 2022, Lagos, NG

University of Benin | Bachelors of Art, Philosophy

APR 2010 - NOV 2014, Benin City, NG

EXPERIENCE

Software Developer | Freelance

SEP 2023 - Present, Lethbridge, AB

- Designed, Developed and maintained a website for a client working with people with special needs.
- Designed a wireframe and prototype using Figma design tool while communicating with the client to gather requirements.
- Developed, deployed and maintained a fully responsive, engaging and interactive website, for clients using React with TypeScript, SASS and GSAP animation library leading to 100% online presence and engagement

Software Developer (Volunteer) | BIPOC Foundation

SEP 2023 - Present, Lethbridge, AB

- Collaborated with the team on project planning and requirements gathering using JIRA.
- Designed a wireframe and prototype using Figma design tool while communicating with the client to gather requirements.
- Advised team on system architecture and design.
- Reporting on annual management meetings aimed at coordinating events for technology businesses in Lethbridge.

Software Developer | BrainStation

SEP 2023 - DEC 2023, Toronto, ON (Teaching Assistant, Contract Full-Time)

 Championed a nurturing environment for 11 junior developers, providing mentorship and effective communication, fostering a culture of innovation and excellence.

- Executed code reviews in JavaScript, React, and Express providing feedback that led to a 90% increase in the effectiveness of the developers and application performance.
- Supervised the successful development of 10 unique full-stack web applications, an example of which is a real-time multiplayer data structures and algorithms game that was built with React on the front end, and API was built using Express.js and MySQL and Mongo DB was used for the database and RabbitMQ and Socket.io were used for messaging. Docker was used for containerizing the application.

Software Developer | AAJIMATICS Incorporated

Nov 2022 - Jun 2023, Remote (Contract Full-time)

- Collaborated with team members to design and build SQL database using MySQL database management system and build APIs and integrate third-party APIs on e-health product using Express.js and spring boot working with Docker and Kubernetes clusters.
- Developed an in-house full-stack client management system on Node.js, Express.js, and React.js using TypeScript, and implemented state management using Redux that led to a 10% boost in productivity.
- Collaborating with the team to maintain code bases on GitHub, performing code reviews on pull requests. Effectively planning project sprints on JIRA, and working with agile scrum methodologies.

Software Engineer | BELDORE Technologies

Apr 2022 - Nov 2022, Lagos, NG

- Developed and maintained responsive websites, using the power of React Hooks to create dynamic and reusable components on React.js, consistently meeting design specifications and accessibility standards for 2 satisfied clients.
- Collaborated with a team of 2 frontend developers and a Developer lead in building reusable frontend components for a vacation booking application on React and maintaining versions of the application on GitHub.

Software Developer | Freelance

Jul 2018 - Apr 2022, Lagos, NG

- Designed and Developed responsive website for clients.
- Developed engaging, responsive and professional websites for clients demonstrating a strong understanding of WordPress, HTML, CSS, and JavaScrip
- Built a website for a book cover design company.

Business Development & Partnership Relations | JEDEBB Resources

May 2015 - Jul 2018, Lagos, NG

- Developed and maintained a comprehensive company brochure that boosted marketing by 25%.
- Secured 5 new clients for the company.
- Collaborated with clients to gather requirements for customized and focused employee training programmes.